

9871278366



swatijain.12@gmail.com



New Delhi, India

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

 C, C++, Core Java, HTML, SQL, Python

OPERATING SYSTEMS

Operating Systems,
Familiarity with Linux

EDUCATION

Master of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering (2010 - 2012)

- UP Technical University (Ideal Institute of Technology, Ghaziabad, UP, India)
- Percentage: 69.25% [First Division]

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering (2003 - 2007)

- UP Technical University (Galgotia College of Engineering & Technology, Greater Noida, UP, India)
- Percentage: 64.5%

Swati Jain Kansal

Summary

13 years of experience including 10.5 years of experience as faculty in the field of Computer Science. Areas of expertise include Programming in 'C', Java, VB.net, Python, Fundamentals of Information Technology, DBMS and Software Testing.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Teaching Experience

August 2010 to September 2023 (10.5 Years)

- 1. Netaji Subhas University of Technology, New Delhi Sep 2022 to Present] (1 yr.)
 - Worked as a Visiting Faculty in Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.)
 - Courses Undertaken: Web Technology, Operating Systems, Theory of Formal Languages and Automata, Python
- Integrated Institute of Technology (IP University), New Delhi Aug 2016 to Mar 2022] (5.5 yrs.)
 - Worked as a Visiting Faculty in BCA
 - Courses Undertaken: E-Commerce, Core Java, VB.net, Free and Opensource Systems, PHP, Software Testing
- 3. Bhai Parmanand Institute of Business Studies, Delhi Aug 2014 to May 2015 (10 months)
 - Worked as Visiting Faculty
 - Courses Undertaken: Fundamentals of Information Technology, Database Management System
- Ideal Institute of Technology (UP Technical University), Ghaziabad, U.P. Aug 2010 to Jul 2013 (3 years)
 - Worked as Full Time Lecturer in Computer Science & Engineering Department
 - Courses Undertaken: Computer Concepts & Programming in 'C', Operating System

Industry Experience

January 2008 to June 2010 (2 Years 6 Months)

1. Software Engineer at SDG Software India Pvt. Ltd. (Jan'08 - Sep'09)

Roles & Responsibility

- · Experience of directly interacting with US based Clients
- Understanding of the Software Development Lifecycle
- Worked as a developer on multiple technologies like: PHP, JavaScript, XSLT, XML, MYSQL and HTML
- 2. Bharat Electronics Limited Central Research Laboratory (Oct'09 Jun'10)

RELEVANT ACADEMIC RECORD

Master of Technology: Research Area: Software Testing

- The main goal and motive of the thesis was to provide evidence that Mutation Testing techniques and tools reached a state of maturity and applicability.
- Architecture for a mutation testing tool called "mute java" was proposed which would have a significant improvement over existing tools in java.

Paper Publications in An International Journal

 Swati Jain, Shikha Singh," A Study on Equivalent Mutants Detecting Techniques", VSRD International Journal of Computer Science and Information Technology, Vol. III, Issue V, ISN No: 2319-2224/May 2013, pp.179-186

Extension / Outreach Activities

- External Practical examiner to GGSIP & UP Technical University
- Paper evaluator in Board of Technical Education (Govt. of NCT), Pitampura, Delhi

PERSONAL DETAILS

Father's Name

Mr. R.K. Jain

Husband's Name

Mr. Anubhav Kansal 26th December 1985

Date of BirthAddress

D-301, Fakhruddin Memorial CGHS, Plot No. – 18, Sector – 10,

Dwarka, New Delhi-110075